(Phone call ends)
(Chirping)
Look at that!
All right, good. Now stand to the right of the tree.
All right, around here?
Yeah, get closer to the tree. A little more to the left.
Around here?
All right, right there. Good.
Come on, let's wrap this up quickly.
What on earth are they doing?
They seem to be peering through something. What can you see, Mr. Earthworm?
Oh, I can't see a thing until nightfall.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
Listen, my babies are about to hatch. What if something happens?
I've seen that before. They're surveying the land.
What do they plan on doing once it's surveyed?
Beats me!
Hmm, that really is a massive tree.
Heheh, you're so right, Boss.
Hmm, that tree really bothers me.
I know!
Cricket is my friend, hehe, we're the best of pals~
Mokku, you're good at that~
But, but... Hey, Mokku!
Good morning!
Mokku, could you come here for a second?
No way, I'm heading to school. I don't have time to dilly-dally.
I know, but it won't take long. Please!
I have to be a good boy if I want to become human. Don't tempt me.
It's hard enough for me to stay on track as it is.
Some human adults gathered around the Oak Tree, and they're doing something strange.
What? Around the Oak Tree?
I have a bad feeling something awful is about to happen.
What on earth are they trying to do?
Please, go find out what's going on.
I can't understand human speech.
You say you've got a bad feeling?
All right, I'll go.
Thanks, Mokku. Let's go!
All right!
Mokku...
Mokku is actually trying to do something to help Giorgio today.
Well, I won't scold him for straying this time. Let's just see how this plays out.
Huh? Aren't they just surveying the land?
The one setting up the pole is Franco's dad.
I know that.
You want to know what on earth they're doing that for, right? Got it. I'll go ask for you.
Franco's dad, good morning!
Franco's dad!
What?
Oh, it's Mokku. What are you measuring this place for?
Huh?
What's this?
Hey! What are you peeking at?!
This isn't for kids to see!
Fix my neck, my neck! Boss, shall we head down the mountain soon?
Huh, they left.
Hey, Mokku. Did you find out?
No, no good.
And you were our only hope.
Aw, don't look so sad.
I know, I'll ask Franco. All right?
Is that true, Franco?
Yeah, it's true.
I heard Dad talking to Mom about it last night.
It's gonna be great once the amusement park is built!
But Franco, what on earth is an amusement park?
It's a playground for kids like us.
They're building an amusement park with all kinds of rides.
It's gonna be amazing!
It's a kids' paradise, with a carousel, a Ferris wheel, and tons of rides!
[[NO AUDIO]]
Wow, that sounds like it'll be a lot of fun.
Come on, you'll get to play there every day, so you must be looking forward to it, too.
Yeah, I hope it's finished soon.
Hey, Franco, tell your dad to hurry up and build it! / Sure, will do. I'll tell him.
Franco's dad is really amazing.
You bet he is!
Huh? An amusement park here?
It's the quietest place in the village, with the best view.
They say they're building a huge one, with tons of things to play on.
But this Oak Tree will be all right, won't it, Mokku?
Huh?
That's right. They wouldn't cut it down, would they?
Well... I didn't ask about that.
What if it gets chopped down? What will we do? We won't have anywhere to live!
Mokku, that's not going to happen, right?
Don't ask me. It's not like I'm the one building it.
Mokku, this affects you, too!
It's useless if you don't ask the most important thing! Hurry up and find out!
B-But... Just go! If you dawdle, I'll poke your butt like last time!
A-All right, I get it! Mokku, hurry up, hurry!
Quit dragging your feet!
I'm going, I'm going!
We're counting on you, Mokku!
I wonder if Mokku will be okay. He doesn't seem very reliable.
Man, that scared me. Why does everyone get so worked up?
Ugh, I got dirt in my mouth. Geez.
Why do I have to rush around like this? Give me a break.
Oh no, look what I did.
It has nothing to do with me anyway.
Whether that Oak Tree gets chopped down or whatever happens to it, it's not my problem.
You idiot!
You ungrateful brat!
That Oak Tree is your mother!
My mother?
Listen to me!
The Fairy who gave you life lives in that Oak Tree! You big fool!
The Fairy who gave me life...
Mokku, I am the Fairy of the Oak Tree, your home.
I have heard Grandfather's wish, and I have come to give you life.
Grant life to the wooden puppet, Mokku.
[[MUSIC]]
And Mokku, do you remember? When you fell into this stream and were almost smashed to pieces in the waterfall basin...
Who was it that reached out a hand to save you?
Ha ha ha!
Look out!
Help me!
Hang in there, Mokku!
Mokku, hold on!
Be brave!
If you give up over something like this, you can never become human.
Now, take heart and climb out.
Do you really not care if that Oak Tree gets chopped down?
I'll ask Franco's dad to see if they're really going to cut down the Oak Tree.
That's it, that's the spirit! I'm counting on you, Mokku.
Hey, wait up. I'm coming too.
Cheers!
To celebrate the President's new project...
I made a success of the coastal tourism business. This time, I'll make sure that mountain amusement park succeeds without fail!
Once it's built, huge crowds will be packing in! Which means money will come rolling in... Yes, I'll do anything for money! I have to build the amusement park as soon as possible!
To do that, first we've gotta chop down that huge oak tree on top of the mountain! I knew it... Mokku! They really are going to cut down the Oak Tree! Are you just going to let them, Mokku?!
The Oak Tree... The Oak Tree is going to be cut down...
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Please stop!
Ah!
Stop it! Please stop!
A dream...? Thank goodness it was just a dream...
All right! I'll definitely protect that Oak Tree!
I'm the village headman... did you come running to Silk Hat too?
Um, Grandfather is back. Sorry, Koro-papa!
Huh?
Who is it?
Me?
There are two or three of you.
What is it? What do you want?
Is it true they're building an amusement park on the Oak Tree's mountain?
Yeah, that's right. And it's going to be something incredible.
Could you please stop?
Huh? Yeah, sure, like I'd stop!
Wh-What?
That Oak Tree on my hill... I mean, all kinds of animals and insects live in that tree.
So please, can't you leave it the way it is?
Stop messing around!
What kind of nonsense are you talking? Shut up!
Give your stupidity a rest!
Please. Stop it.
Shut up!
Please, listen to me! I'm begging you!
Like hell we'll listen to that!
Ah! Mokku!
Ah!
Oh, that's terrible.
Mokku, are you all right?
Spouting such nonsense.
Come on, Mokku, pull yourself together!
Oh, no, he can't go to school like this.
What a cruel thing to do.
Now, if you've learned your lesson, hurry up and go home.
Giorgione!
Hey!
Hey! Give my hat back!
You little prankster, get down from there right now!
Hyahaha! Serves you right!
Making a fool out of me... just watch what I'll do!
Go get it!
Oh, tease him! This is fun!
Look out! Giorgio, stop! Stop!
Shut up!
My hand...
It snapped...
Ah!
Giorgio!
Hang in there!
Serves you right!
Grandpa, Giorgio will be able to fly again, won't he?
The injury isn't serious. He'll heal if he rests for a day or two.
That's a relief, Giorgio.
If the Oak Tree is going to be chopped down, who cares if my wings heal or not.
What are you saying, Giorgio?
Because it's true! Everyone's home will be gone!
There's no point in living like that.
Now then, Mokku's hand... let's see.
Oh, that's right. I used up the rest of the oak wood when I fixed Mokku's leg the other day.
Don't worry anymore. I'll go negotiate with Vittorio.
Really, Grandpa?!
The plateau with that Oak Tree has the most beautiful view in the village.
I am completely against building some gaudy playground in a place like that.
The sensible villagers will surely oppose it too.
We'll all stand together and protect the Oak Tree.
Please do, Grandpa.
Isn't that great, Giorgio?
Yeah. I want to go tell the squirrels and wild birds right away.
Mokku, look, your arm is all finished.
Being a wooden puppet makes you easy to repair, thankfully. There, how's that?
Thank you, Grandpa.
Huh, that's weird.
What's wrong with it?
Hm? What's the matter?
Grandpa, it won't move like it used to.
It isn't made of oak, so it probably won't move right away. Don't worry, it'll move once you get used to it.
Well, I have to go talk to them.
I wonder...
What the hell are you babbling about? An old geezer like you has no business interfering!
Vitore, please. This is a peaceful mountain. I want you to leave it in peace.
The mountain is far more beautiful as it is than with some amusement park. You just stick to your woodcarving, old man! Building a leisure land there is already a done deal. Now get lost!
No matter how much you object, it won't change a thing, old man! B-But, Vitore!
Then there's really no saving the Oak Tree... Forgive me, it's all because I'm so powerless. Let us pray to God to protect the Oak Tree...
That's the only thing we can do right now.
God, please protect the Oak Tree. Please hear my prayer.
Hurry up and get ready! Do you have all the tools?
Yes!
All right, let's begin! Cut that tree down!
Ah, at last... has my final moment come...?
Huh?
What?
Aaargh!
Ah! It's Mokku!
Stop it! Stop cutting down the Oak Tree!
This is none of your business!
Stop! Please, I'm begging you!
Get lost!
Keep getting in our way and I'll smash you to pieces first!
Hey! Wait! Stop! I beg of you!
Listen here, old man! Get in our way again and you won't be spared!
That's right, I have official permission from the town hall!
Grandpa, if they cut down the Oak Tree, I'd rather die!
All right, boys, get to it!
Heave!
Mokku, what are you saying?
But Grandpa, Mama... the Oak Tree is going to be cut down!
Mokku, pray. Pray to God.
What are you muttering...? God! Please! Please save the Oak Tree!
Please save the Oak Tree... Save my mother!
I beg you! Take my life instead!
Please... Please save my mother!
Dear God!
All right, let's do this!
Go ahead.
Dear God!
God, please help us!
Help!
Forget it!
Run!
Help!
Brother!
Help me!
Somebody help me!
Vittorio, take my hand!
Grandfather, you shouldn't help a guy like him!
Fool!
Come on, grab on, Vittorio!
I-I'm sorry...
Hold on, Mokku. Almost there.
Thank you, Mokku. Thank you.
I'm sorry. Please forgive me.
You did well, Mokku. Everything is all right now.
Thank goodness! I'm so glad!
It's all thanks to Mokku!
Mokku, you did so well protecting the Oak Tree.
Thank you. And you did well to help others with that disabled hand.
I will give you a reward. I shall transfer the life of the oak branch struck by lightning into this hand.
(Audio)
Ah! It moves! It's moving!
Grandpa! Grandpa! I-I-It's fixed! My left hand can move!
Is that so? That's wonderful!
The Fairy was right after all! It moves, Grandpa!
Because you tried so hard to protect the Oak Tree, God healed it for you.
If only you were always a good boy like this, I wouldn't have such a hard time.
Mokku is gradually becoming a good boy. (laughter)
Learning that Mokku is at his wit's end after insects ate one of his legs, Kenken and his gang hatch another evil scheme.
In exchange for telling him who can fix his leg, they tell him to break the embankment.
Suspecting nothing, Mokku is tricked into throwing stones at the embankment.
And that night, heavy rain begins to fall,
and an overflowing torrent of water violently assaults the embankment.
Look forward to next week's episode of Kashi no Ki Mokku.